materialtree.com 2015-12-12

# Privacy Policy - Materialtree.com

Your privacy is very important to us.  This privacy policy of materialtree.com ("materialtree"), a trademark of Live More Services Pvt Ltd, Bangalore, India, describes the information we gather, how we share that information and what we do to protect your information on our website, [www.materialtree.com](http://www.materialtree.com/).

Use of the site indicates agreement with this privacy policy. This privacy policy was last updated 6th  December 2013. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [enquiry@materialtree.com](mailto:enquiry@materialtree.com) or +91 96327 88890

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE GATHER?**

Information we automatically collect via industry standard web log files includes the URL from which you visited, the page you are visiting, your computer browser information and your IP address. We may also use automatic data collection device such as "cookies".

Cookies contain specific pieces of information on your computer hard drive, and can be set to store information during a visit or for a longer period of time. Cookies are also used to help streamline your experience on the site, automatically logging you in during future visits, for example. You are free to disable cookies at any time if your browser permits. However, by doing so, you may not be able to use certain features of our site. If you are unable to submit a Get Free Quotes while having cookies disabled, please contact our Customer Care department.

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site.

As a prospective buyer using offerings on our site (such as our Get Free Quotes service) to receive information from or about sellers, you are required to provide additional information so materialtree can deliver these services to you. This includes contact information, basic demographic information, and your purchasing requirements. The information collected can vary according to the different material categories and can be viewed by visiting the different forms located throughout our site. We may also ask you for feedback about our service, which is collected and stored to allow us to continually improve our offerings.

As a supplier using offerings on our site (such as our Get Free Quotes service to receive information from or about prospective buyers), you must provide information that allows us to deliver our service to you. This includes your contact information, information about your desired target markets, and billing information.

We also require you to provide certain information when you request our newsletters, sample lead service or other content or submit information for posting on public areas of this site (e.g., blogs, moderated discussions or bulletin boards).

Additionally, we may request that you provide demographic information. The specific information requested varies according to the different types of content you may request.

Some of the materials included on this site, including advertising, may be served by third parties. These third parties, in the course of serving such materials, may collect information regarding your use of this site and how you respond to e-mail communications, using methods that may include automatic data collection, and may use this information in order to present advertisements or other content that may be of interest to you on both this site and other web sites. Collection, use, disclosure and security of information collected by third parties are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties.

**HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?**

Materialtree uses the information we gather to put buyers and sellers into contact with one another, to provide other features and functionality of this site, to improve your experience on our site through analysis and communication, for other purposes described in this policy, and for purposes disclosed to you when you provide information.

**To Facilitate Transactions:**  Buyers or Vendors will receive emails/ SMS’s and other communications from us to fulfill or facilitate the purpose for which the information was provided or a request to use a service on this site. You cannot opt out of emails that are necessary to provide our services. By using materialtree’s services offered on this site, you agree that we may use your personal information to contact you and deliver information to you related to those services.

**Analysis:**  In our ongoing effort to improve the content and services we offer, we continually analyze the information we receive to identify trends and patterns in user behavior. Your personal information, when used in such a manner, is aggregated with others to amass enough data for such analysis and is not personally identifiable.

**Testimonials and Feedback:**  We sincerely appreciate the feedback we receive from our users. Your feedback, both positive and negative, is forwarded to the appropriate departments at materialtree as necessary so we can continue to monitor and improve the service we provide. We may also share testimonials in our marketing literature but will do so without including personally identifiable information unless we have expressly received your permission to do so. If you would like your testimonial removed, please contact us

**Newsletters:**  Materialtree offers valuable content through email newsletters for both buyers and suppliers. If you no longer wish to receive any newsletter, we encourage you to opt out of these communications by changing your notification preferences as described below.

**Other communications:**  Materialtree may send you email and other communications related to this site, your use of our services and the status of your account, which may include site updates and responses to your inquiries. In addition, materialtree sends periodic surveys and other communications, all of which you can opt out of receiving by changing your notification preferences as described below.

**Third Party Offers:**  We also may use your information to send you e-mail and other communications on behalf of third parties. Each of these communications will include instructions for opting out of receiving future third party offers from us. You may also opt out of receiving third party offers from this Site at any time by sending an e-mail to [enquiry@materialtree.com](mailto:enquiry@materialtree.com) with the subject line "opt out- third party."

**HOW DO WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION WITH OTHERS?**

Our customer information is an important part of our business. As a result, we only disclose this information as described in this section. Our sharing of information to outside parties is described below. As part of our service to customers, we provide information to suppliers/vendors/manufacturers, so that we can fulfill your orders placed.

**Vendors / Suppliers / Manufacturers / Logistics Partners**

To facilitate order processing and delivery, we will share you contact details to our vendors / suppliers  and other parties who will assist in delivery of the ordered items. This includes your basic contact information like name, billing / shipping address, telephone and email contacts.

**Advertisers:**  We may provide your information to third party advertisers (and/or to their service providers on their behalf) to market their products or services under contractual requirement to keep your personally identifiable information confidential and use it only to market and provide (directly and through third parties engaged by them for such purpose) their products or services. You may opt out of such disclosures by sending an e-mail to [enquiry@materialtree.com](mailto:enquiry@materialtree.com) with the subject line: "do **not share.** " We also aggregate information about our collective users for potential advertisers who are interested in understanding whether their offering would be suitable to our audience. This information does not include personally identifiable information like your company name or email address.

**Business Transfers:**  It is possible that our business may be merged with or sold to another business entity. During such a transaction, business information is typically one of the assets shared in the combined entity. In the event that this occurs, your personal information will be protected by the materialtree privacy policy in effect at the time. If your personal information will be used contrary to this policy, you will receive notice as described in the "Notification of Changes" section below.

**Legal Requests:**  materialtree is interested in protecting its members and the community at large. We will release account and other personal information to legal authorities when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law, rules or regulations or to protect persons or property. In addition, materialtree may choose to release information about you to relevant parties in relation to investigations of fraud, piracy or other unlawful activity.

**INFORMATION SECURITY**

Your information is stored on servers that are protected against unauthorized access through the use of safeguards such as "firewalls," encryption and Secure Socket Layers. We utilize many security techniques to protect your personal information. However, it is impossible to guarantee a perfect security system.

**ACCOUNT INFORMATION AND PREFERENCES**

Materialtree provides a number of ways for you to manage your personal information.

**Account information:**  If you need to update your account information, such as your contact email address, you may do so by contacting our Customer Care department at [enquiry@materialtree.com](mailto:enquiry@materialtree.com). Or login to your account and change your profile.

**Notification Preferences:**  You have the ability to "opt out" or unsubscribe from certain e-mail communications, such as periodic surveys and our monthly email newsletter, that are not related to a requested service and/or the status of your account. To update your communication preferences, contact our Customer Care department at [enquiry@materialtree.com](mailto:enquiry@materialtree.com). If you do contact the Customer Care department, please be sure to specify the type of email communication(s) from which you would like to opt out. Information about how to unsubscribe is also included in every communication we send.

**Password:**  Materialtree suppliers may be issued a User ID and password to access their account. As a supplier, you are responsible for all actions taken with your user ID and password, including fees charged to your account. Do not share your password with any third parties, as you may be legally liable for any fees that are incurred. If you believe that your password has been compromised, you should immediately change your password or contact Customer Care at [enquiry@materialtree.com](mailto:enquiry@materialtree.com)

**Data Rentention.**  We will retain your information to continue to offer you products and services. Please contact us if you wish to cancel or request that we no longer use your information this way. We will also retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**CHILDREN**

Persons under the age of 18 are not eligible to use materialtree's services.

**WIDGETS**

Our Web site includes Widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions polls etc). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

**PUBLIC FORUMS**

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, please contact us. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**LEGAL DISCLAIMER**

Although we have attempted to address the various privacy-related issues you are likely to encounter, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this privacy policy. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private from unauthorized access. Also, materialtree contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy policy applies to information collected by materialtree alone.

**NOTIFICATION OF CHANGE**

We may amend this privacy policy for minor changes at any time by posting the amended terms on the Site. All minor amended terms shall be effective upon posting. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you by email or by posting a prominent notice for 30 days prior to the change taking effect.

**CONTACTING US**

If you have any additional questions or comments about materialtree's privacy statement, please contact us:

**Live More Services Pvt Ltd**

**Reg Office:** #28/20, HIG, N V Arcade 2nd Stage, 1st Cross, KHB Colony, Basaveshwarnagar, Bangalore- 560 079

[enquiry@materialtree.com](mailto:enquiry@materialtree.com) / +96327 88890
